TYLER MAINGUY

(647) 926-0313 | tsmainguy@outlook.com

OBJECTIVE SKILLS

To gain hands on experience with machine learning, web development, and software engineering. I have always been fascinated and intrigued by these fields, and how they are constantly changing and developing. I strive to gain knowledge of new technologies that can improve my ability to create flexible and powerful solutions. My experience and hard work ethic make me a great fit on any team.

Beginner Advance
••••
••••
••••
••••
••••
••••

EDUCATION

Queen's University

Sep. 2017 - Present

- o 4th year, Honours Bachelor of Computing and Mathematics [CGPA: 4.03/4.30]
- o Queen's Dean's Honours List
- Full first year credit transfer from University of Guelph, Honors Bachelor of Computing Program [CGPA: 91.4%]

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern at TripAdvisor

May 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Working under the Core Experiences division on the Search and Navigation team
- Assisted on development of the search functionality of a site with millions of hits every day
- Stabilized site errors and corrected bugs in functionality resulting in improvement of user experience
- Wrote sophisticated SQL queries to analyze the patterns of attrition amongst users
- Reviewed code and communicated effectively with teammates to ensure quality of code and architecture

Software Development Intern at DemandHub

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

- One of the first three hires to a VC-funded startup, fifth employee in the company
- o Researched and developed the entire test harness from scratch for both the existing frontend codebase, and the back-end REST API (testing done in Jest and Enzyme)
- o Full stack development of web application components using ReactJS, Node, and MySQL

Teaching Assistant at Queen's University

Sep. 2018 - May 2019

- Teaching assistant in CISC 124, a 2nd-year computing course designed to teach students object-oriented design, architecture, and programming using Java.
- Teaching assistant for CISC 271, a 2nd 4th year class focusing on linear data analysis (linear equations, PCA, matrix decompositions, linear regression).
- o Hosting tutorials/labs where I assist students in understanding material provided in lecture, along with assistance on exercises and assignments, and quiz/exam review
- o Grade assignments submitted throughout the semester